<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Tim Sun</title>
        <link>https://timsun001.github.io/post/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Tim Sun</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://timsun001.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Research on Pinduoduo&#39;s Overseas E-commerce (Temu)</title>
        <link>https://timsun001.github.io/p/t2/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://timsun001.github.io/p/t2/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://timsun001.github.io/p/t2/cover.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post Research on Pinduoduo&#39;s Overseas E-commerce (Temu)" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Temu project was initiated in September 2022. It stands as Pinduoduo&amp;rsquo;s third major strategic initiative following its successes in the domestic e-commerce and grocery delivery sectors. Temu has been of paramount importance within Pinduoduo, with the team being led by Gu Pingping, the former head of Duoduo Grocery. There have even been rumors suggesting that Pinduoduo&amp;rsquo;s founder, Huang Zheng, has returned to the company to provide direction for the Temu project. In February 2023, Temu made waves by securing a 30-second Super Bowl advertisement slot, garnering significant attention as a hot topic at the time. Industry experts are unanimous in their belief that Temu is poised to replace Wish&amp;rsquo;s position in the American e-commerce landscape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this report, we have synthesized the core viewpoints from mainstream research reports and a selection of opinions voiced by American consumers regarding Temu. We aim to provide insights into the potential development prospects of Temu in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/t2/p1_temu%E5%95%86%E4%B8%9A%E6%A8%A1%E5%BC%8F.png&#34;
	width=&#34;4047&#34;
	height=&#34;1925&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/t2/p1_temu%E5%95%86%E4%B8%9A%E6%A8%A1%E5%BC%8F_hu75ce77a85fa2a87ac5af27b86b4eac41_758398_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/t2/p1_temu%E5%95%86%E4%B8%9A%E6%A8%A1%E5%BC%8F_hu75ce77a85fa2a87ac5af27b86b4eac41_758398_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Temu&amp;rsquo;s Business Model&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;210&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;504px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Temu&amp;rsquo;s business model is built upon the foundation of Pinduoduo&amp;rsquo;s robust cash flow, allowing it to rapidly establish its presence in the United States through extensive advertising campaigns. However, considering the disparities between the American and Chinese markets in terms of consumer preferences and competitive landscape, alongside the decision-making tendencies of Temu&amp;rsquo;s management team, &lt;strong&gt;the profitability of Temu&amp;rsquo;s future remains uncertain&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Temu aims to leverage Pinduoduo&amp;rsquo;s domestic sourcing advantages and position itself as a provider of &amp;ldquo;high-quality products at low prices,&amp;rdquo; attempting to replicate Pinduoduo&amp;rsquo;s success path in China. However, this model faces several challenges in the United States:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Without the trust boost provided by the endorsement of a platform like WeChat, Temu may struggle to establish the &amp;ldquo;high-quality products at low prices&amp;rdquo; image among American consumers&lt;/strong&gt;. Pinduoduo&amp;rsquo;s early expansion in China heavily relied on its collaboration with WeChat, which significantly lowered the trust threshold due to widespread sharing among friends and family, thereby rapidly boosting user numbers. In the United States, Temu lacks access to the powerful user acquisition channel of WeChat, which will inevitably prolong the process of building trust with American consumers and lead to higher costs (as discussed later);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Temu might face fiercer competition overseas compared to the domestic market&lt;/strong&gt;. On one hand, the American market features giants like Amazon in the mid-to-high-quality market segment (with a market cap three times that of Alibaba). On the other hand, in the emerging high-value, cost-effective e-commerce market, competitors like SheIn and TikTok exist. SheIn has already established significant consumer trust in the women&amp;rsquo;s fashion vertical and is actively expanding into other categories, while TikTok boasts nearly 1.6 billion global daily active users and years of experience operating overseas traffic. How Temu will carve out a sustainable profit margin in such a competitive environment remains to be observed;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The cost of acquiring overseas traffic might surpass Temu&amp;rsquo;s management team&amp;rsquo;s expectations, possibly necessitating a quicker business model transformation&lt;/strong&gt;. It requires substantial investment to establish trust with consumers and secure a position in intense competition. Moreover, we observe that American social platforms seem to have stricter control over viral marketing of the Pinduoduo kind (discussed later). If the impacts of these controls exceed Temu&amp;rsquo;s management team&amp;rsquo;s expectations, the need to address high traffic and logistics costs might force Temu to compromise on product quality, raise prices, or undertake structural transformations. Regardless of the chosen course of action, Temu&amp;rsquo;s overseas expansion will face further resistance: 1. Lowering product quality would replicate Wish&amp;rsquo;s pitfalls; 2. Price hikes would significantly affect platform traffic and sales, and while increasing prices might become necessary under heavy losses, it is an action of last resort. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://36kr.com/p/2392005566208642&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Reports&lt;/a&gt; suggest that Temu executed a comprehensive price increase for most categories on August 16; 3. Undertaking a shift in category structure might demand substantial subsidies to build user trust (similar to Pinduoduo&amp;rsquo;s billion-dollar subsidies in China). Based on Temu&amp;rsquo;s recent price adjustment, it appears that they do not intend to undertake large-scale subsidy actions in the near term.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Temu Management Team&amp;rsquo;s experience with the successful creation of Duoduo Grocery lends credibility to the project. However, based on our research, comparing the actual experience of Duoduo Grocery with that of Meituan Maicai (a competing grocery delivery service) or other offline grocery shopping experiences, Duoduo Grocery&amp;rsquo;s performance falls short. There have also been complaints from suppliers regarding Duoduo Grocery&amp;rsquo;s bidding policy, with some suppliers expressing concerns that the competitive bidding environment could lead to lower product quality overall. We will delve further into Duoduo Grocery&amp;rsquo;s performance in the following sections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;recommendations&#34;&gt;Recommendations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For suppliers planning to join Temu&lt;/strong&gt;: Temu could be considered as one of the channels to utilize excess production capacity. In the short term, Temu is likely to continue expanding its American operations with subsidies from its parent company Pinduoduo. During this period, collaborations with Temu could be profitable. However, resources should not be overly skewed towards Temu, as this might result in the gradual loss of pricing power or bearing the risk of declining traffic at Temu in the later stages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For investors in Pinduoduo&lt;/strong&gt;: While Pinduoduo&amp;rsquo;s core e-commerce business remains robust, Temu&amp;rsquo;s profitability still holds uncertainty. If Temu is unable to successfully upgrade its brand image and enhance consumer experience, it could even face failure. Investment in Temu should be approached with caution, and the ability to smoothly transition the brand image could become a pivotal factor for its long-term survival in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-observations-from-mainstream-research-reports&#34;&gt;Key Observations from Mainstream Research Reports&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mainstream research reports largely view Temu favorably, believing that Pinduoduo&amp;rsquo;s advantages in domestic supply chains, innovative marketing strategies, and the successful track record of the Duoduo Grocery team will contribute to Temu&amp;rsquo;s success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, most of these research organizations have overlooked the differences between American and Chinese consumers(Hayden Capital is an exception, as staying neutral about Temu&amp;rsquo;s future), as well as the actual shopping experiences of Pinduoduo, Duoduo Grocery, or Temu. Neglecting these factors might lead to an overly optimistic assessment of Temu. We will further discuss our conclusions based on our research into these factors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;zheshang-securities-january-9-2023&#34;&gt;Zheshang Securities (January 9, 2023)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zheshang Securities is bullish on the Temu project and Pinduoduo&amp;rsquo;s stock price. Their main arguments are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Temu has assembled the original team from Duoduo Grocery, with a highly competitive force;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Temu replicates the creative traffic strategies from Pinduoduo&amp;rsquo;s domestic platform, facilitating rapid customer acquisition;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Temu leverages the strong domestic supply chain of Pinduoduo, demonstrating robust supply capabilities;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Temu&amp;rsquo;s recommendation-based e-commerce model surpasses existing search-based models in the overseas market.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/t2/p4_%E6%B5%99%E5%95%86230109.png&#34;
	width=&#34;826&#34;
	height=&#34;1169&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/t2/p4_%E6%B5%99%E5%95%86230109_hu2ea6ebfb1230f05ad60f9de8de02d891_3435213_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/t2/p4_%E6%B5%99%E5%95%86230109_hu2ea6ebfb1230f05ad60f9de8de02d891_3435213_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Research report on Temu released by Zheshang Securities on January 9, 2023)&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;70&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;169px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;hayden-capital-january-5-2023httpshaydencapitalcomwp-contentuploadshayden-capital_pinduoduo-memopdf&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://haydencapital.com/wp-content/uploads/Hayden-Capital_Pinduoduo-Memo.pdf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Hayden Capital (January 5, 2023)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hayden Capital has refrained from making a definitive judgment on the performance of the Temu project for now. Nevertheless, they believe that Pinduoduo&amp;rsquo;s strategic timing in investing in the Temu project demonstrates the exceptional judgment of the management team, thus fostering an optimistic outlook on Pinduoduo&amp;rsquo;s stock price prospects. In regard to viewpoints concerning the Temu project, Hayden Capital&amp;rsquo;s stance is as follows:：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pinduoduo places significant emphasis on the Temu project&lt;/strong&gt;：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The team led by Gu Pingping, who previously spearheaded the Duoduo Maicai project, is at the helm of the Temu project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pinduoduo has acquired valuable talent by luring employees from SheIn with high salaries (3-5 times their previous income).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An estimated investment of around 7 billion RMB is expected within a year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pinduoduo has strategically timed the Temu project&lt;/strong&gt;：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Global economic downturn has resulted in surplus production capacity in Chinese factories.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduced disposable income among American consumers has led them to seek more cost-effective products (with Temu&amp;rsquo;s pricing typically being equivalent to 30%-50% of Amazon&amp;rsquo;s).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Temu will benefit from Pinduoduo&amp;rsquo;s integration of domestic suppliers&lt;/strong&gt;：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pinduoduo&amp;rsquo;s initiatives such as shortening the supply chain and reducing intermediaries have boosted suppliers&amp;rsquo; profit margins. Additionally, they&amp;rsquo;ve introduced automated advertising tools tailored for factory operations, further enhancing suppliers&amp;rsquo; profit potential. The trust established between Pinduoduo and suppliers during this period will serve as a barrier for their future expansion into overseas markets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Traffic presents a primary challenge during overseas expansion for Temu&lt;/strong&gt;：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Without the traffic boost provided by WeChat, Temu faces difficulty in achieving rapid growth overseas similar to its domestic success on Pinduoduo&amp;rsquo;s platform.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TikTok, a direct competitor to Temu, is one of the largest sources of traffic overseas, thereby undermining Temu&amp;rsquo;s traffic acquisition channels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;china-merchants-securitiesnovember-10-2022&#34;&gt;China Merchants Securities(November 10, 2022)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Temu possesses two advantageous aspects that could contribute to its success in overseas competition, according to China Securities:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accumulated mature resources of high-quality, low-cost suppliers and operational capabilities from its domestic business;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learnt from the experiences of its predecessors during international expansion. For instance, it has avoided the platform model utilized by Wish and opted for a self-operated model, ensuring product quality and user experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;China Securities believes that the preliminary annual loss of around 5 billion RMB by Temu is insufficient to significantly impact its parent company&amp;rsquo;s overall profits (315 billion RMB in 2022). In the later stages, Temu is highly likely to transform its business model (from self-operated to platform) and category structure (from low-unit price to high-unit price) to gain greater profit potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;China Securities gives a &amp;ldquo;strongly recommended&amp;rdquo; rating for the stock of Pinduoduo, Temu&amp;rsquo;s parent company. Based on a 3-year profit forecast (year-on-year growth rates of 115%, 39%, 30%), China Securities believes that its stock price could potentially increase from $59 to $92 per share (using November 9, 2022, stock price as reference).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/t2/p3_%E6%8B%9B%E5%95%86221110.png&#34;
	width=&#34;826&#34;
	height=&#34;1169&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/t2/p3_%E6%8B%9B%E5%95%86221110_hua7c75fd684772959e0cb7fb34922d6e5_4559604_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/t2/p3_%E6%8B%9B%E5%95%86221110_hua7c75fd684772959e0cb7fb34922d6e5_4559604_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Research report released by China Securities on November 10, 2022&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;70&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;169px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;zheshang-securities-september-28-2022&#34;&gt;Zheshang Securities (September 28, 2022)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Temu holds advantages in terms of demand background, organizational capability, and business model, while simultaneously facing challenges such as high logistics costs, rising traffic expenses, and competition from e-commerce giants. Its development is promising, but its success will depend on its actual performance after business expansion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demand background: A global economic downturn and decreased per capita purchasing power. Temu&amp;rsquo;s entry into the low-cost market segment exhibits strong growth momentum.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organizational capability: The Temu team, primarily built upon the foundation of Duoduo Maicai, is poised to replicate the operational capabilities and successful experiences of Duoduo Maicai.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Business model: Drawing lessons from the failures of Wish, Temu has rigorously curated its merchant selection and product range, elevating user experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/t2/p2_%E6%B5%99%E5%95%86220928.png&#34;
	width=&#34;832&#34;
	height=&#34;460&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/t2/p2_%E6%B5%99%E5%95%86220928_hufe9ff07126fcbd4ebb14bed14d1b333c_277513_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/t2/p2_%E6%B5%99%E5%95%86220928_hufe9ff07126fcbd4ebb14bed14d1b333c_277513_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Research report released by Zheshang Securities on September 28, 2022&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;180&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;434px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;american-public-perception-of-temu&#34;&gt;American Public Perception of Temu&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through analyzing the most upvoted comments in Reddit posts related to &amp;ldquo;Temu&amp;rdquo;, we&amp;rsquo;ve extracted key points of discussion among users. From this, we&amp;rsquo;ve summarized the following opinions held by the American public regarding Temu:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concerns about Temu&amp;rsquo;s low prices&lt;/strong&gt;. In discussions with high upvote counts, opinion leaders express apprehensions that low prices might come at certain costs, including:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unethical labor relations&lt;/strong&gt;. Some users point out that low-priced goods often involve labor exploitation. Additionally, counterarguments suggest that labor exploitation isn&amp;rsquo;t exclusive to Temu and that Temu&amp;rsquo;s offerings at least come at lower prices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personal privacy breaches&lt;/strong&gt;. Some users suspect that Temu might exchange low-priced goods for users&amp;rsquo; personal information, which could serve as the primary source of profit for Temu.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lack of expectations for product quality&lt;/strong&gt;. Many users consider Temu to be akin to &amp;ldquo;Wish 2.0&amp;rdquo;, or even worse. Despite Temu&amp;rsquo;s efforts to improve product quality through self-operated model, users&amp;rsquo; perception of this improvement seems limited. Some users express that spending on Temu is &amp;ldquo;generally worth the money, but half of the items in an order might have quality issues.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, we believe that Temu&amp;rsquo;s current low prices are primarily supported by cash flow subsidies from its parent company, rather than through labor exploitation. Additionally, under the stringent personal information regulations in the United States, the risk and reward of profiting from reselling personal information are not proportional and do not align with Temu&amp;rsquo;s original intention of expanding its overseas business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, these pieces of information undoubtedly reflect the lack of trust from the American public in Temu. Temu may need to consider how to reshape the perception of its low-price positioning in the minds of users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the criticism regarding product quality, given Temu&amp;rsquo;s strategy of pursuing extremely low prices, there might indeed be a higher likelihood of quality issues with many products. This is a challenge that Temu will need to allocate significant resources to overcome in the later stages; otherwise, it could potentially repeat the mistakes of Wish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/t2/p5_%E5%8A%B3%E5%B7%A5%E7%A6%8F%E5%88%A9.png&#34;
	width=&#34;832&#34;
	height=&#34;216&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/t2/p5_%E5%8A%B3%E5%B7%A5%E7%A6%8F%E5%88%A9_hu9ca757986ca607ae366ace3f065fb31e_72008_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/t2/p5_%E5%8A%B3%E5%B7%A5%E7%A6%8F%E5%88%A9_hu9ca757986ca607ae366ace3f065fb31e_72008_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Concerns of American Users Regarding Temu&amp;rsquo;s Labor Welfare&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;385&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;924px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/t2/p6_%E4%B8%AA%E4%BA%BA%E4%BF%A1%E6%81%AF%E5%AE%89%E5%85%A8.png&#34;
	width=&#34;832&#34;
	height=&#34;282&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/t2/p6_%E4%B8%AA%E4%BA%BA%E4%BF%A1%E6%81%AF%E5%AE%89%E5%85%A8_hu0879e5077e4d1d13371a4bc6f32b0125_74872_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/t2/p6_%E4%B8%AA%E4%BA%BA%E4%BF%A1%E6%81%AF%E5%AE%89%E5%85%A8_hu0879e5077e4d1d13371a4bc6f32b0125_74872_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Concerns of American Users Regarding Personal Information Security&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;295&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;708px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/t2/p7_%E4%BA%A7%E5%93%81%E8%B4%A8%E9%87%8F.png&#34;
	width=&#34;832&#34;
	height=&#34;462&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/t2/p7_%E4%BA%A7%E5%93%81%E8%B4%A8%E9%87%8F_hu633702e0505d50ed32208e7276425c4f_99199_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/t2/p7_%E4%BA%A7%E5%93%81%E8%B4%A8%E9%87%8F_hu633702e0505d50ed32208e7276425c4f_99199_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Low Expectations of American Users for Temu&amp;rsquo;s Product Quality&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;180&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;432px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/t2/p8_wish.png&#34;
	width=&#34;832&#34;
	height=&#34;298&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/t2/p8_wish_hud87d07220517d500c43a9a6ebd7d4b80_47943_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/t2/p8_wish_hud87d07220517d500c43a9a6ebd7d4b80_47943_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;American Users Perceive Temu as Wish 2.0&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;279&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;670px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/t2/p13_wish%E8%82%A1%E4%BB%B7.png&#34;
	width=&#34;832&#34;
	height=&#34;430&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/t2/p13_wish%E8%82%A1%E4%BB%B7_hub6a432ea384499ff1b9ad4502f0e98ac_63561_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/t2/p13_wish%E8%82%A1%E4%BB%B7_hub6a432ea384499ff1b9ad4502f0e98ac_63561_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Wish Stock Price Decline Over the Past Two Years Amid User Loss&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;193&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;464px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dissatisfaction with Temu&amp;rsquo;s Marketing Strategies&lt;/strong&gt;. Within the posts garnering significant likes, American users have expressed their dissatisfaction with Temu&amp;rsquo;s marketing strategies in two main aspects:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Displeasure with Temu&amp;rsquo;s Brainwashing Marketing&lt;/strong&gt;: Some users have reported that Temu&amp;rsquo;s products and services do not align with its advertising slogan, &amp;ldquo;Shop Like a Billionaire.&amp;rdquo; These users believe that billionaires would not purchase such low-cost products. Temu&amp;rsquo;s heavy investment in advertising may be backfiring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Suspicions of Temu as a Scam&lt;/strong&gt;: Until June 2023, &amp;ldquo;Scam&amp;rdquo; has consistently been one of the most common keywords in Reddit&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Temu&amp;rdquo; search results. Users generally find Temu&amp;rsquo;s offerings perplexing: on one hand, the low prices raise concerns about product quality and personal privacy, and on the other hand, the user experience is disjointed from the advertising claims. Furthermore, many American users have had poor shopping experiences with Wish, leading to heightened caution regarding Temu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/t2/p9_scam.png&#34;
	width=&#34;832&#34;
	height=&#34;436&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/t2/p9_scam_hud08c6a7ea86172eb8346c3e20b20b62c_163046_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/t2/p9_scam_hud08c6a7ea86172eb8346c3e20b20b62c_163046_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;User dissatisfaction with Temu&amp;rsquo;s excessive junk marketing messages, suggesting Temu is a scam&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;190&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;457px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, Temu&amp;rsquo;s impression among the American public bears a striking resemblance to Pinduoduo&amp;rsquo;s early days in China. Pinduoduo gradually improved its brand image among consumers, mainly through substantial subsidies and the support of social networks like WeChat. However,unlike Pinduoduo, Temu lacks the flow of WeChat&amp;rsquo;s user base, and given the overall financing challenges faced by Chinese internet companies, it remains uncertain whether Temu will have the capacity and resources to improve its image among the American public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, we&amp;rsquo;ve observed that executing Pinduoduo-style viral marketing in the United States is not straightforward. During this research, Reddit had already closed numerous Temu invite code sharing subreddits and posts, whereas WeChat had a relatively open attitude toward viral marketing sharing in Pinduoduo&amp;rsquo;s early days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/t2/p10_banned.png&#34;
	width=&#34;832&#34;
	height=&#34;360&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/t2/p10_banned_hu10d0cd51f483040bba0ec8efe86a30db_57306_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/t2/p10_banned_hu10d0cd51f483040bba0ec8efe86a30db_57306_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Reddit has closed many posts sharing Temu invite codes&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;231&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;554px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, it is likely that mainstream research reports have underestimated the differences between American consumers and Chinese consumers. Compared to Chinese consumers, American consumers place greater emphasis on labor welfare and personal privacy, implying higher trust-building costs. Moreover, the internet landscape in the United States is vastly different from China&amp;rsquo;s. Without the support of WeChat&amp;rsquo;s user base and facing stricter regulations on viral marketing, Temu may encounter customer acquisition costs beyond what the management team anticipated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;temu-teams-previous-work-duoduo-grocery&#34;&gt;Temu Team&amp;rsquo;s Previous Work: Duoduo Grocery&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mainstream research institutions generally view the Duoduo Grocery team favorably, believing that it rapidly captured a significant portion of the online fresh produce market in a short time. However, public opinions differ significantly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consumer Side&lt;/strong&gt;: The fluctuation in pickup point quality has been a source of criticism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On one hand, pickup points vary significantly in terms of hardware facilities. Small, low-traffic offline stores like tea shops and laundromats have become ideal hosts for Duoduo Grocery. Some users have reported that certain pickup points lack refrigerators. In our own test orders, pickup points often managed goods haphazardly, requiring consumers to spend over 10 minutes sorting their orders from a pile of items. This model inevitably leads to numerous order mismatches. In our test, a 500g order of grape was divided into two boxes (each containing 250g), and consumers could easily take the wrong items without checking the order weight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, pickup points depend on store ownership, and store transfers or closures are not uncommon. When a store closes or changes ownership, it not only affects the current orders but also necessitates a lengthy process for custumers to rebuild trust with other pickup points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/t2/p11_%E5%A4%9A%E5%A4%9A%E4%B9%B0%E8%8F%9C.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;828&#34;
	height=&#34;1316&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/t2/p11_%E5%A4%9A%E5%A4%9A%E4%B9%B0%E8%8F%9C_huda478768a09c4bfa10a1bbba6099841f_71565_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/t2/p11_%E5%A4%9A%E5%A4%9A%E4%B9%B0%E8%8F%9C_huda478768a09c4bfa10a1bbba6099841f_71565_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Duoduo Grocery pickup points are densely distributed, low-traffic offline stores like tea shops and laundromats have become ideal hosts for Duoduo Grocery&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;62&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;151px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supplier Side&lt;/strong&gt;: Some suppliers have complained about Duoduo Grocery&amp;rsquo;s bidding system, suggesting that in this competitive environment, the likelihood of inferior products displacing high-quality ones is high.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question:How&amp;rsquo;s the experience shopping on Duoduo Grocery&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reply of a disspointed vegetable farmer:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a vegetable farmer, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been a supplier on DuoDuo Grocery for three months now. In January this year, someone from my village who works as a quality inspector at DuoDuo Grocery approached me, suggesting I become a supplier on their platform. Since most people these days prefer to stay home and order groceries through their phones, the prospect seemed promising. Plus, it was a fellow villager, so I trusted the recommendation. After completing the necessary procedures, I embarked on the journey of being a supplier.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I cultivate celery, and since there aren&amp;rsquo;t many celery suppliers on DuoDuo Grocery, I became the sole provider. This unique position allowed me to sell over a thousand portions per day, with each portion weighing 300 grams. After accounting for expenses like plastic bags, labor, and shipping fees, I could make about 2 cents per portion. This translated to three to four hundred dollars a day, which is ostensibly more than what many people make. However, things took a turn after just two weeks. Suddenly, they informed me that they no longer needed my celery. When I inquired about the reason, the folks at DuoDuo Grocery brushed me off, claiming they simply weren&amp;rsquo;t planning to offer celery anymore. I was left speechless. I could sell my produce at the local market, but a couple of days later, I saw celery back on DuoDuo Grocery&amp;rsquo;s shelves.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I asked that same acquaintance to inquire on my behalf. He found out and told me that it was because the other supplier was selling their celery for two cents less per portion. I bought a portion myself and was disappointed with the quality. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t fathom why such subpar produce was being put up for sale. The quality was so poor that I doubted anyone would want it. As expected, within days, negative reviews flooded in, sales plummeted, and the celery was taken down. Then, DuoDuo Grocery approached me again, asking me to continue supplying. This time, they wanted 150-gram portions, but at half the price. It seemed their strategy was to cut costs by reducing portion size and price, attracting more customers. And it worked—within days, they were selling over three thousand portions daily.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But for me, it became a headache. Costs went up; with more portions, my employees couldn&amp;rsquo;t keep up, necessitating hiring another person. Plastic bag usage doubled, and each crate could only hold fifty portions. Previously, 300 grams were fifty portions, and now, even with 150 grams, it was limited to fifty portions, requiring extra trips and fuel. Now, making two hundred dollars a day was a blessing. Then came the troubles. Due to an employee&amp;rsquo;s mistake, one crate was short by ten portions, resulting in a fine of four thousand dollars. That was relatively mild—another supplier who sold cabbage faced even worse. They sold over eight thousand portions daily, and due to oversight, two crates were left behind, incurring a fine of forty-five thousand dollars. After half a year, they practically worked for nothing. There were many similar incidents.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So, to those considering joining in, I&amp;rsquo;d advise careful consideration. As for me, I&amp;rsquo;ll quit once my contract is up. And to all the suppliers on DuoDuo Grocery, I have this to say: for those who criticize the quality of the produce, look at the prices. Farmers like me are in the minority; most source from us and resell to DuoDuo Grocery to make a profit from the margin. They can&amp;rsquo;t afford good produce, so they end up with second-rate goods. One mishap wipes out half a month&amp;rsquo;s earnings. If not for the contracts, many would have left already. Customers aren&amp;rsquo;t happy with the quality, suppliers aren&amp;rsquo;t making money, but DuoDuo Grocery is thriving. These days, we suppliers have a saying: we use the money from selling produce to pay our employees&amp;rsquo; salaries; the fines are where DuoDuo Grocery really makes its money.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, while Duoduo Grocery may indeed possess the ability to leverage smaller capital to gain a larger market share in the early stages of the project, they may weaken the importance of maintaining user experience and supplier relationships in exchange. The latter is a crucial factor in whether the project can achieve long-term profitability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Temu has shown promise in its early stages of business expansion, but it remains unclear whether it can sustainably enhance user experience, maintain mutually beneficial relationships with suppliers, and withstand the fierce competition for overseas traffic. Based on current American public sentiment and Temu&amp;rsquo;s team&amp;rsquo;s past experiences, the future development of Temu does not appear optimistic. The next steps will need to focus on how Temu can improve user experience and transform its brand image to avoid slipping into a scenario akin to becoming &amp;ldquo;Wish 2.0.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Exploring the Male Beauty Market</title>
        <link>https://timsun001.github.io/p/r3_eng/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://timsun001.github.io/p/r3_eng/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://timsun001.github.io/p/r3_eng/cover.png" alt="Featured image of post Exploring the Male Beauty Market" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-points-of-this-article&#34;&gt;Key Points of This Article&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rise of the Men&amp;rsquo;s Beauty Market&lt;/strong&gt;: With the surge in e-commerce and localization trends, the men&amp;rsquo;s beauty and skincare market is gaining increasing attention. While the women&amp;rsquo;s market is highly competitive, the men&amp;rsquo;s market is emerging. Men&amp;rsquo;s skincare and beauty needs have expanded from basic cleansing to advanced skincare and basic makeup, leading to rapid market growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Potential Growth in Men&amp;rsquo;s BB Cream Market&lt;/strong&gt;: The men&amp;rsquo;s basic makeup market, with men&amp;rsquo;s BB cream as a representative product, has significant growth potential. By comparing pricing differences between men&amp;rsquo;s and women&amp;rsquo;s cleansing and BB cream products, we believe that there is a 20% to 30% potential price increase in men&amp;rsquo;s BB creams. Currently, men&amp;rsquo;s BB cream has low penetration, high concentration, and low pricing, indicating an opportunity in the mid-to-high price segment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unmet Demand in the Men&amp;rsquo;s BB Cream Market&lt;/strong&gt;: Users are not satisfied with the experience of top men&amp;rsquo;s BB cream products, particularly in terms of whitening and cakey appearance. Optimizing product performance to meet user expectations will be crucial in attracting users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-rise-of-the-mens-beauty-and-skincare-industry-leading-the-industry-by-27-percentage-points&#34;&gt;The Rise of the Men&amp;rsquo;s Beauty and Skincare Industry, Leading the Industry by 27 Percentage Points&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the rise of e-commerce and the trend of localization in the cosmetics industry, the women&amp;rsquo;s market has been the main battlefield for mainstream beauty and skincare brands. However, in recent years, the competition in the women&amp;rsquo;s beauty and skincare market has intensified. Perfect Diary, for example, has captured the mid-to-low-end market through low prices and promotional strategies. Following that, Flower Knows, with a massive fan base backed by Li Jiaqi, has established itself in the high-priced market with its Chinese-style design. Recently, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Caitang&lt;/a&gt; has emerged as a strong contender in the female beauty and skincare market on Little Red Book. To compete with these brands head-on, newcomers require exceptional operational and financing capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, the beauty ideals of young men from the internet generation have undergone significant changes. Men&amp;rsquo;s demand for beauty and skincare products has evolved from &amp;ldquo;cleansing&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;advanced skincare&amp;rdquo; (typical categories include &amp;ldquo;facial serums&amp;rdquo;) and &amp;ldquo;basic makeup&amp;rdquo; (typical categories include &amp;ldquo;men&amp;rsquo;s BB cream&amp;rdquo;). Data shows rapid growth in beauty and skincare categories for men. As seen in the chart below, since 2017, the growth rate of men&amp;rsquo;s skincare products has gradually outpaced that of the overall cosmetics industry in China, with a projected 27 percentage point difference by 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r3_eng/p3_%E8%A1%8C%E4%B8%9A%E5%A2%9E%E9%80%9F.png&#34;
	width=&#34;2433&#34;
	height=&#34;1375&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r3_eng/p3_%E8%A1%8C%E4%B8%9A%E5%A2%9E%E9%80%9F_hu0689439a6435ac11681cee1188d73174_252555_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/r3_eng/p3_%E8%A1%8C%E4%B8%9A%E5%A2%9E%E9%80%9F_hu0689439a6435ac11681cee1188d73174_252555_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Figure 1: Growth Rate of Men&amp;rsquo;s Skincare Products Compared to the Cosmetics Industry in China. Data Source: iResearch&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;176&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;424px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, under the dual influence of intensified competition in the women&amp;rsquo;s beauty and skincare market and changing beauty ideals among men, the men&amp;rsquo;s beauty and skincare market is becoming a new growth point for many brands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-mens-beauty-and-skincare-market-represented-by-mens-bb-cream-offers-approximately-threefold-growth-potential&#34;&gt;The Men&amp;rsquo;s Beauty and Skincare Market, Represented by Men&amp;rsquo;s BB Cream, Offers Approximately Threefold Growth Potential&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the refinement and advancement of demand, the men&amp;rsquo;s beauty and skincare industry can be roughly divided into five stages: cleansing, basic skincare, advanced skincare, basic makeup, and advanced makeup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cleansing&lt;/strong&gt;: This includes categories such as facial cleansers, shampoos, and body wash.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Basic Skincare&lt;/strong&gt;: This includes skincare sets, facial creams, face masks, toners, sunscreens, mists, and shaving gels, among others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advanced Skincare&lt;/strong&gt;: This includes facial serums, eye creams, and more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Basic Makeup&lt;/strong&gt;: This includes BB creams, perfumes/colognes, concealers, styling products, and more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advanced Makeup&lt;/strong&gt;: This includes lipsticks, eyeshadows, contouring products, makeup removers, and more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r3_eng/p2_%E5%93%81%E7%B1%BB%E5%88%86%E9%98%B6%E6%AE%B5.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1772&#34;
	height=&#34;1014&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r3_eng/p2_%E5%93%81%E7%B1%BB%E5%88%86%E9%98%B6%E6%AE%B5_hu472af681ab988a1a559cf7b8aaf76f06_135470_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/r3_eng/p2_%E5%93%81%E7%B1%BB%E5%88%86%E9%98%B6%E6%AE%B5_hu472af681ab988a1a559cf7b8aaf76f06_135470_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Figure 2: Stages and Market Sizes of Men&amp;rsquo;s Beauty and Skincare Demand (TikTok Channel). Source: Grey Pig Data&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;174&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;419px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on data from TikTok channels, transaction volumes in the men&amp;rsquo;s beauty and skincare market are still concentrated in the more basic stages of &amp;ldquo;cleansing&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;basic skincare.&amp;rdquo; However, when combining data from the domestic and international beauty markets, it is estimated that there is still approximately threefold growth potential in men&amp;rsquo;s basic makeup:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The table below shows the number of paying customers for the top 200 products in the categories of cleansing and BB cream. The ratio of transaction volumes between the two reflects the penetration rate of BB cream. It is evident that the penetration rate of BB cream among female beauty and skincare users is 20.1%, while among male beauty and skincare users, it is only 7.9%. &lt;strong&gt;Compared to the Chinese female market, the Chinese male basic makeup market still has approximately threefold growth potential.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;According to a report from the Korean Food and Drug Administration in March 2019, 36.7% of Korean men use face masks, and &lt;strong&gt;19.4% use BB cream&lt;/strong&gt;. Young Korean men aged 20-29 use an average of 15 different types of cosmetics per month. &lt;strong&gt;Compared to the Korean male market, the Chinese male basic makeup market also has approximately threefold growth potential.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r3_eng/p8_BB%E9%9C%9C%E6%B8%97%E9%80%8F%E7%8E%87.png&#34;
	width=&#34;500&#34;
	height=&#34;140&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r3_eng/p8_BB%E9%9C%9C%E6%B8%97%E9%80%8F%E7%8E%87_hu27012aab3739ad26b672cad8ba7a5a2b_26373_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/r3_eng/p8_BB%E9%9C%9C%E6%B8%97%E9%80%8F%E7%8E%87_hu27012aab3739ad26b672cad8ba7a5a2b_26373_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Figure 3: Penetration Rate of BB Cream. Source: Taobao&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;357&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;857px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;potential-market-opportunities-in-the-mid-to-high-price-segment-for-mens-bb-cream&#34;&gt;Potential Market Opportunities in the Mid-to-High Price Segment for Men&amp;rsquo;s BB Cream&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further analysis of pricing for cleansing and BB cream products reveals that there is a nearly 11% price difference between men&amp;rsquo;s and women&amp;rsquo;s cleansing products (median prices: 53 RMB for men and 59 RMB for women). However, the price difference for BB cream products is significantly higher, at 51% (60 RMB for men and 91 RMB for women).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r3_eng/p7_%E5%AE%9A%E4%BB%B7%E5%88%86%E5%B8%83.png&#34;
	width=&#34;300&#34;
	height=&#34;414&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r3_eng/p7_%E5%AE%9A%E4%BB%B7%E5%88%86%E5%B8%83_hu7964ff5110caddeeba5f9c67f8a65379_35192_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/r3_eng/p7_%E5%AE%9A%E4%BB%B7%E5%88%86%E5%B8%83_hu7964ff5110caddeeba5f9c67f8a65379_35192_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Figure 4: Distribution of Pricing for Cleansing and BB Cream Products. Source: Taobao&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;72&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;173px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The differences between men&amp;rsquo;s and women&amp;rsquo;s BB creams mainly lie in the following aspects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Women&amp;rsquo;s BB creams come with more accessories, including BB cream cases, cushions, and mirrors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Women&amp;rsquo;s BB creams have more complex functions. In addition to the coverage and oil control functions of men&amp;rsquo;s BB creams, they also include moisturizing, sunscreen, isolation, and long-lasting effects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r3_eng/p5_BB%E9%9C%9C%E4%BA%A7%E5%93%81%E5%9B%BE.png&#34;
	width=&#34;500&#34;
	height=&#34;238&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r3_eng/p5_BB%E9%9C%9C%E4%BA%A7%E5%93%81%E5%9B%BE_hu765efa24e3afb5eca4b7c5b25cc08a40_170421_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/r3_eng/p5_BB%E9%9C%9C%E4%BA%A7%E5%93%81%E5%9B%BE_hu765efa24e3afb5eca4b7c5b25cc08a40_170421_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Figure 5: Comparison of Typical Women&amp;rsquo;s BB Creams and Men&amp;rsquo;s BB Creams&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;210&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;504px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r3_eng/p6_BB%E9%9C%9C%E5%95%86%E5%93%81%E5%90%8D%E8%AF%8D%E4%BA%91.png&#34;
	width=&#34;500&#34;
	height=&#34;533&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r3_eng/p6_BB%E9%9C%9C%E5%95%86%E5%93%81%E5%90%8D%E8%AF%8D%E4%BA%91_hua16a1ab2da783cca5e4ff0e95fa4c2ca_130810_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/r3_eng/p6_BB%E9%9C%9C%E5%95%86%E5%93%81%E5%90%8D%E8%AF%8D%E4%BA%91_hua16a1ab2da783cca5e4ff0e95fa4c2ca_130810_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Figure 6: Word Cloud for BB Cream Product Names&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;93&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;225px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The additional accessories and increased complexity of women&amp;rsquo;s BB creams to some extent contribute to their higher costs, subsequently leading to higher prices. However, it is estimated that the cost increase due to accessories and additional functions is only about 5 to 10 RMB (approximately 3 to 10 RMB for accessories and 2 to 3 RMB for additional functions). Even considering the cost increase resulting from accessories and increased functionality, women&amp;rsquo;s BB creams are still priced 30% to 40% higher than men&amp;rsquo;s BB creams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking into account the pricing difference in basic cleansing products between men and women, &lt;strong&gt;we believe there is a 20% to 30% potential price increase in men&amp;rsquo;s BB creams&lt;/strong&gt;, and businesses that can better meet user demands in the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;future are likely to capture this market segment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;unmet-demand-in-the-mens-bb-cream-market&#34;&gt;Unmet Demand in the Men&amp;rsquo;s BB Cream Market&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some negative reviews of a leading men&amp;rsquo;s BB cream product highlight user dissatisfaction and experience issues during usage. Consumers generally feel that the product&amp;rsquo;s effects are not as described in advertisements and promotions, leading to issues like whitening, cakey appearance, and an unnatural look. Many users point out that the product&amp;rsquo;s coverage is poor and does not effectively conceal blemishes and spots, resulting in an unnatural appearance. Additionally, some consumers complain about the product&amp;rsquo;s lack of long-lastingness, as it tends to smudge and become oily shortly after application, failing to meet their expectations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among these issues, &amp;ldquo;not causing whitening&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;even coverage without caking&amp;rdquo; are the most frequently mentioned demands. New brands entering the market can focus on optimizing their products in these two areas to meet user expectations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-not-causing-whitening&#34;&gt;1. Not Causing Whitening&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r3_eng/p9_%E5%81%87%E7%99%BD.svg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Figure 7: Examples of Negative Reviews Mentioning &amp;ldquo;Whitening.&amp;rdquo;&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-even-coverage-without-caking&#34;&gt;2. Even Coverage Without Caking&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r3_eng/p10_%E5%8D%A1%E7%B2%89.svg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Figure 8: Examples of Negative Reviews Mentioning &amp;ldquo;Caking&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Even Coverage.&amp;rdquo;&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;estimation-of-bb-cream-costs&#34;&gt;Estimation of BB Cream Costs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned earlier, the cost increase for accessories in women&amp;rsquo;s BB creams is estimated to be around 3 to 10 RMB, and the cost increase for additional functions is estimated to be around 2 to 3 RMB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The wholesale prices of BB cream accessories (cases, cushions, mirrors) on 1688.com are approximately 3 to 10 RMB. We can consider this as the cost increase for accessories in women&amp;rsquo;s BB creams.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Similarly, BB creams with claims of sunscreen, moisturization, and other functions have a wholesale price increase of about 2 to 3 RMB.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r3_eng/p11_bb%E9%9C%9C%E7%9B%92%E5%AE%9A%E4%BB%B7.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1224&#34;
	height=&#34;364&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r3_eng/p11_bb%E9%9C%9C%E7%9B%92%E5%AE%9A%E4%BB%B7_huc32497190c8959ef32f31aaa93b80515_389014_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/r3_eng/p11_bb%E9%9C%9C%E7%9B%92%E5%AE%9A%E4%BB%B7_huc32497190c8959ef32f31aaa93b80515_389014_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Figure 9: Wholesale Prices of BB Cream Accessories&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;336&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;807px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Density-Based Clustering Algorithm</title>
        <link>https://timsun001.github.io/p/s2_eng/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://timsun001.github.io/p/s2_eng/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://timsun001.github.io/p/s2_eng/cover.png" alt="Featured image of post Density-Based Clustering Algorithm" /&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;previous-context&#34;&gt;Previous Context&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/s1_eng/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;previous study on Xiaohongshu note title clustering&lt;/a&gt;, we initially classified the results using BERT output, reduced the dimensions of the classification results using T-SNE, and finally identified three types of notes: &amp;ldquo;Makeup Tutorial,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Second-hand Trade,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Commercial Promotion.&amp;rdquo; Obviously, the final step heavily relies on human judgment, making it difficult to scale and less objective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;density-based-clustering-algorithm&#34;&gt;Density-Based Clustering Algorithm&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time, we have added clustering based on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1706.03113.pdf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DBSCAN&lt;/a&gt; on top of what we did previously (DBSCAN is a density-based clustering algorithm that adjusts clustering results based on &amp;ldquo;minimum distance within the same class&amp;rdquo; (eps) and &amp;ldquo;minimum number of samples&amp;rdquo; (min_samples)). Compared to traditional KMeans clustering (which adjusts clustering results by specifying the number of clusters), this algorithm has several advantages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No need to specify the number of clusters (clearly, we cannot know the total number of clusters in Xiaohongshu titles).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Points with no clear cluster relationships will be assigned to other classes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, applying this algorithm also comes with a challenge: how to find suitable values for the eps and min_samples parameters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;parameter-tuning&#34;&gt;Parameter Tuning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;using-silhouette-score-as-an-evaluation-metric&#34;&gt;Using Silhouette Score as an Evaluation Metric&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearly, if eps or min_samples are set too large, it will result in a large number of points being grouped into the same class, leading to the loss of useful information, and vice versa. To address this issue, we first introduced the &amp;ldquo;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;#silhouette-score&#34; &gt;Silhouette Score&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; as an evaluation metric for the algorithm, testing the &amp;ldquo;Silhouette Score&amp;rdquo; for different parameters. Ideally, a larger &amp;ldquo;Silhouette Score&amp;rdquo; is better (indicating clearer classification boundaries). However, in the task mentioned above, a large Silhouette Score can have two negative effects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduced total number of clusters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increased number of samples in the &amp;ldquo;other&amp;rdquo; class.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;introducing-percentage-of-other-class-samples-and-total-number-of-clusters-to-optimize-the-evaluation-metric&#34;&gt;Introducing &amp;ldquo;Percentage of Other Class Samples&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Total Number of Clusters&amp;rdquo; to Optimize the Evaluation Metric&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To overcome the above negative effects, we introduced the &amp;ldquo;Percentage of Other Class Samples&amp;rdquo; and used the harmonic mean of this metric with the Silhouette Score as the clustering score (the higher, the better). At the same time, we calculated the total number of clusters for different parameters. The table below shows the clustering scores (weighted_silhouette) for some parameter settings.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/s2_eng/%E7%AE%97%E6%B3%95%E8%AF%84%E5%88%86.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1654&#34;
	height=&#34;1402&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/s2_eng/%E7%AE%97%E6%B3%95%E8%AF%84%E5%88%86_hu9427fa2b231c5d3c7070556e3d91c439_163137_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/s2_eng/%E7%AE%97%E6%B3%95%E8%AF%84%E5%88%86_hu9427fa2b231c5d3c7070556e3d91c439_163137_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Clustering Scores&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;117&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;283px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final solution we selected was the one with the highest weighted_silhouette score among cases where n_labels is greater than 10. The final clustering result is as shown in the following figure. We not only clearly distinguished the three types of notes (&amp;ldquo;Makeup Tutorial,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Second-hand Trade,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Commercial Promotion&amp;rdquo;) identified by the previous solution but also identified an additional 7 classes of notes.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/s2_eng/%E8%81%9A%E7%B1%BB%E6%95%88%E6%9E%9C.png&#34;
	width=&#34;2000&#34;
	height=&#34;1600&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/s2_eng/%E8%81%9A%E7%B1%BB%E6%95%88%E6%9E%9C_hubdfcf3b8245a662f0eaedc4b937f8257_1152908_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/s2_eng/%E8%81%9A%E7%B1%BB%E6%95%88%E6%9E%9C_hubdfcf3b8245a662f0eaedc4b937f8257_1152908_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Clustering Result&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;125&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;300px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;appendix&#34;&gt;Appendix&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;silhouette-score&#34;&gt;Silhouette Score&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Silhouette Score is a metric used to evaluate the quality of clustering. It aims to measure both the compactness and separation of samples in clustering results. It helps us understand how well a clustering algorithm has divided samples into similar clusters with distinct boundaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically, for each sample, the Silhouette Score considers two factors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The similarity of a sample to other samples in the same cluster: It measures the average distance between the sample and other samples within its cluster. A smaller value indicates that the sample is tightly packed with other samples in its cluster, indicating better clustering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The similarity of a sample to samples in the nearest different cluster: It measures the average distance between the sample and samples in the nearest cluster other than its own. A larger value indicates that the sample is further from samples in other clusters, also indicating better clustering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering both of these factors, the Silhouette Score&amp;rsquo;s value ranges from -1 to 1:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A higher positive value indicates that the sample is closer to other samples in its cluster and farther from samples in other clusters, indicating better clustering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A value close to zero indicates that the distance of the sample to samples in its own cluster is similar to the distance to samples in other clusters, indicating unclear clustering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A negative value indicates that the sample is closer to samples in other clusters, indicating poor clustering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, a Silhouette Score closer to 1 indicates better clustering, while a score closer to -1 or less than 0 indicates worse clustering. When using the Silhouette Score, we aim to find the highest score to achieve the best clustering results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;view-interactive-data-on-tableau-public&#34;&gt;View Interactive Data on Tableau Public&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://public.tableau.com/app/profile/t.s1480/viz/_16905304270770/sheet0&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;View the interactive data on Tableau Public&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Unveiling the Battle of Recommendations in the Xiaohongshu Beauty Industry</title>
        <link>https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/cover.png" alt="Featured image of post Unveiling the Battle of Recommendations in the Xiaohongshu Beauty Industry" /&gt;&lt;h1 id=&#34;executive-summary&#34;&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This report delves into the marketing strategies and market competition status of two major domestic cosmetics brands - Caitang and Huaxizi. To compare the performance of these two brands on Xiaohongshu (Little Red Book) and the impact of Xiaohongshu recommendations on brand sales, we analyzed nearly 100,000 Xiaohongshu notes data in the cosmetics and skincare categories, as well as nearly 10,000 Taobao-related comment data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on Xiaohongshu note data, we found that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cosmetics and skincare notes are highly popular on Xiaohongshu, with many users browsing notes related to shopping experiences. Influencers in these categories also gain a significant number of followers, ranking at the top for various content types.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the cosmetics and skincare categories, international brands have significantly higher visibility (measured by likes and comments) compared to domestic brands, approximately 2.4 times higher. Commercial notes in the skincare category are growing faster than in the cosmetics category, suggesting that skincare marketing relies more on off-platform recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When comparing different brands&amp;rsquo; performance on Xiaohongshu, Caitang stands out among domestic brands. In Q2 2023, the number of video notes related to Caitang significantly surpassed Huaxizi, especially in makeup tutorial notes. This implies that Caitang-related recommendations on Xiaohongshu are more likely to be the result of voluntary actions by beauty bloggers rather than commercial promotions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on product review data, we found that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proportion of mentions of &amp;ldquo;being recommended&amp;rdquo; in Caitang&amp;rsquo;s reviews is 4.7 times that of Huaxizi, indicating that Caitang&amp;rsquo;s extensive recommendations on Xiaohongshu have yielded substantial results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proportion of mentions of &amp;ldquo;repurchase&amp;rdquo; in Huaxizi&amp;rsquo;s reviews is 2.5 times that of Caitang, reflecting Huaxizi&amp;rsquo;s significant advantage in retaining loyal customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, Caitang has successfully transformed the recommendation effect on Xiaohongshu into sales and is poised to further capture market share from Huaxizi in the future. Meanwhile, Huaxizi maintains strong competitiveness through its loyal customer base. As the culture of recommendations continues to evolve and user word-of-mouth accumulates, Caitang may leverage its advantage among beauty influencers to secure a leading position in the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/001.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;4958&#34;
	height=&#34;7017&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/001_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_1850945_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/001_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_1850945_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;70&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;169px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/002.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;4958&#34;
	height=&#34;7017&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/002_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_1231827_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/002_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_1231827_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;70&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;169px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/003.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;4958&#34;
	height=&#34;7017&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/003_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_1761695_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/003_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_1761695_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;70&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;169px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/004.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;4958&#34;
	height=&#34;7017&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/004_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_1449042_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/004_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_1449042_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;70&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;169px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/005.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;4958&#34;
	height=&#34;7017&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/005_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_1641335_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/005_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_1641335_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;70&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;169px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/006.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;4958&#34;
	height=&#34;7017&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/006_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_1390418_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/006_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_1390418_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;70&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;169px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/007.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;4958&#34;
	height=&#34;7017&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/007_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_1087049_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/007_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_1087049_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;70&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;169px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/008.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;4958&#34;
	height=&#34;7017&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/008_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_1362750_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/008_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_1362750_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;70&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;169px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/009.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;4958&#34;
	height=&#34;7017&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/009_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_1087016_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/009_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_1087016_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;70&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;169px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/010.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;4958&#34;
	height=&#34;7017&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/010_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_1554629_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/010_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_1554629_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;70&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;169px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/011.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;4958&#34;
	height=&#34;7017&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/011_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_1738742_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/011_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_1738742_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;70&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;169px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/012.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;4958&#34;
	height=&#34;7017&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/012_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_960881_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/012_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_960881_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;70&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;169px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/013.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;4958&#34;
	height=&#34;7017&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/013_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_1667311_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/013_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_1667311_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;70&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;169px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/014.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;4958&#34;
	height=&#34;7017&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/014_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_1327614_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/014_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_1327614_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;70&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;169px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/015.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;4958&#34;
	height=&#34;7017&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/015_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_1250596_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/015_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_1250596_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;70&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;169px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/016.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;4958&#34;
	height=&#34;7017&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/016_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_2349436_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/r2_eng/R2/016_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_2349436_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;70&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;169px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Semantic Information Mining in Xiaohongshu Notes</title>
        <link>https://timsun001.github.io/p/s1_eng/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://timsun001.github.io/p/s1_eng/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://timsun001.github.io/p/s1_eng/cover.png" alt="Featured image of post Semantic Information Mining in Xiaohongshu Notes" /&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-nlp-information-mining-in-the-era-of-social-e-commerce&#34;&gt;I. NLP Information Mining in the Era of Social E-commerce&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xiaohongshu (Little Red Book) note data contains a wealth of information, but its content often tends to be divergent. If we can focus on the part related to consumer decision-making, it can help consumer goods brands better understand consumers and improve product development and marketing efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using traditional word segmentation and frequency statistics, it is challenging to identify differences between various pieces of information. This article introduces an efficient and effective method to cluster different types of information in Xiaohongshu effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/s1_eng/p1.png&#34;
	width=&#34;686&#34;
	height=&#34;624&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/s1_eng/p1_hub379b53efbae407affc5defcc794b322_453650_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/s1_eng/p1_hub379b53efbae407affc5defcc794b322_453650_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Chart 1&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;109&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;263px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/s1_eng/p2.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1540&#34;
	height=&#34;1627&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/s1_eng/p2_hu7846b560b61886d114af488c764e3b09_506381_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/s1_eng/p2_hu7846b560b61886d114af488c764e3b09_506381_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Chart 2&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;94&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;227px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ii-comparing-three-analysis-approaches-word-frequency-statistics-semantic-clustering-and-sentence-semantic-clustering&#34;&gt;II. Comparing Three Analysis Approaches: Word Frequency Statistics, Semantic Clustering, and Sentence Semantic Clustering&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;models-used-by-the-three-approaches&#34;&gt;Models Used by the Three Approaches&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/s1_eng/p5.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1485&#34;
	height=&#34;307&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/s1_eng/p5_hu36293c3340b249fdf1bf1a2bb0b35b82_66190_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/s1_eng/p5_hu36293c3340b249fdf1bf1a2bb0b35b82_66190_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Chart 3&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;483&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;1160px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;1-word-frequency-statistics&#34;&gt;1. Word Frequency Statistics&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Word frequency statistics are the most traditional method in NLP analysis. In this task, it performs poorly primarily due to two issues:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The most frequent words are often semantically meaningless particles or punctuation marks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Due to the highly scattered nature of topics on Xiaohongshu, many semantically meaningful words have low frequencies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/s1_eng/p4.png&#34;
	width=&#34;660&#34;
	height=&#34;2209&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/s1_eng/p4_hu91df84232e7c9767bc042e288aa21b83_145955_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/s1_eng/p4_hu91df84232e7c9767bc042e288aa21b83_145955_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Chart 4&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;29&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;71px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/s1_eng/p3.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1659&#34;
	height=&#34;1035&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/s1_eng/p3_hu983ae6caf4f3c53bb9eda7c40f45adfa_86104_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/s1_eng/p3_hu983ae6caf4f3c53bb9eda7c40f45adfa_86104_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Chart 5&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;160&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;384px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;2-semantic-clustering&#34;&gt;2. Semantic Clustering&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basic principle of semantic clustering is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Split sentences into words.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encode words, defining each encoding as a dimension of the sentence (if a word appears in the sentence, mark it as 1; otherwise, mark it as 0).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use clustering algorithms to calculate the similarity between sentences or use dimension reduction algorithms to map high-dimensional information to two dimensions for visualization. For intuitive understanding, we chose the latter method (dimension reduction).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Semantic clustering based on word meanings has the following limitations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It does not consider the relevance of words themselves. To address this, a significant amount of manual annotation work is required for synonym correction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The results of word clustering largely reflect the same information as word frequency statistics, lacking information richness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The results of word clustering may focus on word-level meanings and lack sentence-level understanding, which limits its usefulness. For example, Area A in the chart focuses on mentioning &amp;ldquo;female college students,&amp;rdquo; Area B on &amp;ldquo;contouring,&amp;rdquo; Area C on &amp;ldquo;highlighting,&amp;rdquo; and Area D on &amp;ldquo;Huaxizi.&amp;rdquo; These commonalities have limited marketing decision-making value for brands.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/s1_eng/p6.png&#34;
	width=&#34;2635&#34;
	height=&#34;2475&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/s1_eng/p6_hu4b73ff1eac4a31663f91a0b73ecb7f8b_3590781_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/s1_eng/p6_hu4b73ff1eac4a31663f91a0b73ecb7f8b_3590781_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Chart 6&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;106&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;255px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;3-sentence-semantic-clustering&#34;&gt;3. Sentence Semantic Clustering&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core idea behind sentence semantic clustering is to use pre-trained NLP models, combined with some degree of fine-tuning, to achieve more accurate understanding of semantics. We used &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1810.04805&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;BERT&lt;/a&gt; (BERT is a pre-trained NLP model based on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1706.03762&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;attention mechanisms&lt;/a&gt; released by Google Labs in 2018). Even without any fine-tuning, its clustering results are quite satisfactory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basic principle is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose an appropriate pre-trained model.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In this case, we selected BERT&amp;rsquo;s output, where the first dimension represents sentence classification, with a total of 768 dimensions. Each dimension can take values between 0 and 1 (corresponding to BERT&amp;rsquo;s output classifying sentences into a maximum of 768 classes, with each dimension&amp;rsquo;s value representing the probability of the sentence being assigned to a certain class).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use clustering algorithms to calculate the similarity between sentences or use dimension reduction algorithms to map high-dimensional information to two dimensions for visualization. For intuitive understanding, we chose the latter method (dimension reduction).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Applying this method, we found significant differences in the number of notes for two brands in three regions: A, B, and C. These three areas are:
A. Makeup tutorial notes
B. Second-hand trade notes
C. Commercial promotion notes
Compared to the results of semantic clustering, sentence semantic clustering provides a more macroscopic and human-intuitive understanding of information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/s1_eng/p1.png&#34;
	width=&#34;686&#34;
	height=&#34;624&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/s1_eng/p1_hub379b53efbae407affc5defcc794b322_453650_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/s1_eng/p1_hub379b53efbae407affc5defcc794b322_453650_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Chart 7&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;109&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;263px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;iii-optimization-space-for-sentence-semantic-clustering&#34;&gt;III. Optimization Space for Sentence Semantic Clustering&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the results of sentence semantic clustering, further manual annotation and fine-tuning of the BERT model based on Xiaohongshu&amp;rsquo;s corpus are expected to yield more desired results.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Emerging Trends in Douyin(Tiktok) E-commerce Snack Sales</title>
        <link>https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/cover.png" alt="Featured image of post Emerging Trends in Douyin(Tiktok) E-commerce Snack Sales" /&gt;&lt;h1 id=&#34;execution-summary&#34;&gt;Execution Summary&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The snack category of Douyin e-commerce has experienced remarkable growth in the past 4 months, with a 1.5-fold increase in sales and a 4-fold increase in sales volume, despite a 67% decrease in the average selling price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This change is primarily influenced by two subcategories: &amp;ldquo;Pastry/Snacks/Bread&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Walnuts/Nuts/Roasted Snacks.&amp;rdquo; These two subcategories show significant differences in sales data between January and May.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In January, products with a high unit price of over 100 RMB accounted for 9.3% and 19.7% of total sales in these two categories, respectively. Products with unit prices below 10 RMB accounted for 21.4% and 11.1%.
By May, the percentage of products with unit prices over 100 RMB had decreased to 0.5% and 1.7%, while products with unit prices below 10 RMB had increased to 66.8% and 73.0%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This difference is attributed to a shift in user demand from &amp;ldquo;gift-giving scenarios&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;leisure scenarios.&amp;rdquo; By comparing the changes in product names between these scenarios, we have summarized the &amp;ldquo;long-term user demand&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;seasonal demand related to gift-giving.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on our analysis, we suggest that in the current Douyin e-commerce snack category, competition is fiercer in scenarios similar to May&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;leisure scene,&amp;rdquo; with lower profit margins (as indicated by the mainstream pricing of 9.9 RMB and an average commission rate of 16.8%). On the other hand, scenarios similar to January&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;gift-giving scene,&amp;rdquo; while having a shorter time window, have less competition and higher profit margins (mainstream prices above 100 RMB and an average commission rate of less than 2%). This also means that brands or sellers can have more flexible operational space in terms of their supply chain and operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, we recommend that brands and sellers carefully consider entering the &amp;ldquo;leisure scene&amp;rdquo; when entering the snack category, to avoid getting caught in price wars. Instead, they can consider entering the snack category during the &amp;ldquo;gift-giving scene&amp;rdquo; window to establish their business on the Douyin platform in a risk-controlled manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/R1/001.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;4958&#34;
	height=&#34;7017&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/R1/001_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_1837110_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/R1/001_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_1837110_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;70&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;169px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/R1/002.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;4958&#34;
	height=&#34;7017&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/R1/002_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_1023668_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/R1/002_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_1023668_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;70&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;169px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/R1/003.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;4958&#34;
	height=&#34;7017&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/R1/003_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_1446359_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/R1/003_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_1446359_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;70&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;169px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/R1/004.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;4958&#34;
	height=&#34;7017&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/R1/004_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_851191_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/R1/004_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_851191_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;70&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;169px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/R1/005.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;4958&#34;
	height=&#34;7017&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/R1/005_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_2594956_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/R1/005_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_2594956_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;70&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;169px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/R1/006.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;4958&#34;
	height=&#34;7017&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/R1/006_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_1858716_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/R1/006_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_1858716_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;70&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;169px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/R1/007.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;4958&#34;
	height=&#34;7017&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/R1/007_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_2410429_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/R1/007_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_2410429_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;70&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;169px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/R1/008.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;4958&#34;
	height=&#34;7017&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/R1/008_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_2315319_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/R1/008_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_2315319_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;70&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;169px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/R1/009.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;4958&#34;
	height=&#34;7017&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/R1/009_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_2026955_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/R1/009_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_2026955_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;70&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;169px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/R1/010.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;4958&#34;
	height=&#34;7017&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/R1/010_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_1925786_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/R1/010_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_1925786_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;70&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;169px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/R1/011.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;4958&#34;
	height=&#34;7017&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/R1/011_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_2468659_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/R1/011_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_2468659_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;70&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;169px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/R1/012.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;4958&#34;
	height=&#34;7017&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/R1/012_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_1897955_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/R1/012_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_1897955_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;70&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;169px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/R1/013.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;4958&#34;
	height=&#34;7017&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/R1/013_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_1669975_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/R1/013_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_1669975_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;70&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;169px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/R1/014.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;4958&#34;
	height=&#34;7017&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/R1/014_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_2146457_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://timsun001.github.io/p/r1_eng/R1/014_hu955ce26ac8f8727df313d2b022a0ee4f_2146457_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;70&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;169px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
